<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>KaiChu</title><link>https://kaichu.io/</link><description>Life is unique by how you shape it</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 08:09:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kaichu.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Golang Alfred Workflow Generator Ak</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/golang-alfred-workflow-generator-ak/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 08:09:25 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/golang-alfred-workflow-generator-ak/</guid><description>A generator for golang alfred workflow that helps you create boilerplate code.</description></item><item><title>Golang Base Alfred Code Sign and Notarize</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/golang-base-alfred-code-sign-and-notarize/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 14:29:41 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/golang-base-alfred-code-sign-and-notarize/</guid><description>After solving the problem with Gon Sign ErrSecInternalComponent in the previous post, we can now use Gon to sign and notarize code in Github Action to create a complete release process.</description></item><item><title>Devfest22 Taipei Skaffold2 Deep Dive</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/devfest22-taipei-skaffold2-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 15:44:20 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/devfest22-taipei-skaffold2-deep-dive/</guid><description>Skaffold V2 extends the platforms and architectures supported by Skaffold, introduces Cloud Run as a supported deployer, and now supports building and deploying from ARM and x86 architectures. Skaffold V2 also provides enhanced support for CI/CD and GitOps workflows, introduces Skaffold rendering, validation and kpt integration. Most importantly, all existing Skaffold configurations are fully compatible with Skaffold V2, so upgrading from V1 is as easy as running a Skaffold fix</description></item><item><title>Gon Sign ErrSecInternalComponent</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/gon-sign-errsecinternalcomponent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 16:12:38 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/gon-sign-errsecinternalcomponent/</guid><description>Gon is a tool developed by Hashicorp founder Mitchell Hashimoto that makes the whole process of code signing easy. This article documents the problems I encountered with Gon code sign and how I solved them.</description></item><item><title>Devfest22 Taichung Cloud Workstation Introduction</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/devfest22-taichung-cloud-workstation-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 05:43:36 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/devfest22-taichung-cloud-workstation-introduction/</guid><description>Google announce Gloud Workstation preview version on 2022/10/11. In this year DevFest Taichung 2022, I share Cloud Workstation Introduction. Introduce how to set up Cloud Workstation, use cases and Demo</description></item><item><title>Cloud Workstation With Hugo Env</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/cloud-workstation-with-hugo-env/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 13:27:09 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/cloud-workstation-with-hugo-env/</guid><description>The preconfigured base images provided by Cloud Workstations contain only a minimal environment with IDE, basic Linux terminal and language tools and a sshd server. To expedite the environment setup of specific development use cases, you can create custom container images that extend these base images to pre-install tools and dependencies and that run automation scripts.</description></item><item><title>Alfred Open Chinese Convert</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/alfred-open-chinese-convert/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 14:42:06 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/alfred-open-chinese-convert/</guid><description>Since Mac OS finally removed support for Python2 in 12.3, the workflows written in Python2 in Alfred 4 are no longer available. The amowu/alfred-chinese-converter I was using before is also no longer updated (it's still in Alfred 2). So I built one with Golang + awgo + opencc, eliminating the dependency on Python, and Alfred upgrades no longer run into Python version problems.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Gokit Todo to GAE With Cloud Build From Github Repo</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/deploy-gokit-todo-to-gae-with-cloud-build-from-github-repo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 07:16:36 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/deploy-gokit-todo-to-gae-with-cloud-build-from-github-repo/</guid><description>gokit-todo, gokit-todo-frontend are applications developed with low dependencies on code suites and simple tasks on Kubernetes. We can easily migrate to Google App Engine for CI/CD development process using Google Cloud Build and Github repo.</description></item><item><title>Wason Language Translator CLI</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/wason-language-translator-cli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 04:49:16 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/wason-language-translator-cli/</guid><description>Recently, I have encountered the need of document localization in my work environment, and the commonly used Google Translate, DeepL Translate, and Wason Language Translator all provide document translation. Wason Language Translator provides a free Lite solution, so I use Wason Language Translator offers a free Lite solution, so use Golang to package Language Translator - IBM Cloud API for cli to make it easier to use.</description></item><item><title>Taiwan Hong Kong Cloud Study Jam Guide</title><link>https://kaichu.io/posts/taiwan-hong-kong-cloud-study-jam-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 13:55:32 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kaichu.io/posts/taiwan-hong-kong-cloud-study-jam-guide/</guid><description>2022 第一場 Taiwan Hong Kong Cloud Study Jam 已經開始, 時間從 2022/1/19 - 2022/2/7。GDG Cloud Taipei 也舉辦了 Taiwan &amp; Hong Kong Cloud Study Jam Together 邀請大家在 2022/1/25 19:30 - 21:30 上線一起完成 Cloud Study Jam, 在 Meetup 活動開立之後有朋友寫信來問開通的問題，所以還是整理了一下資料來幫助新朋友順利通開取得30 天免費的Google Cloud Skills Boost 訂閱</description></item></channel></rss>